## **Profile**

Accomplished IT Leader leading teams focused on DevOps transformation enterprise wide. Decades of web development and automation experience help inform decisions about direction, and enables growth of junior team members. Current focus is on accelerating the adoption of culture, process, and tooling to support DevOps and Site Reliability Engineering. A passion for technology and continuous learning driving toward delivering quality, automated, fast, and reliable systems. Not afraid to fail fast and learn from mistakes.

## Skills

DevOps

jQuery

**SRE** 

• GitLab

JavaScript

• Splunk

Python

• Kubernetes

• Linux

Docker

- Embedded Programming
- Web Applications
- Career Development
- Interviewing
- Conference Speaking

# Accomplishments

- Took over leadership of a team that had fractured and lost trust and built the appropriate relationships and team cohesion to allow them to push forward. Took team members from being order takers to leaders in the organization
- Helped design, implement, and set the direction for a brand new Technology Operations Center including live dash-boarding and dynamic application performance and capacity monitoring
- Implemented the first SRE based team in the organization starting with embedding Tier 2 operations staff inside of application development teams. At the same time, the oper-

ations team took steps to begin to own and manage system and site stability, resiliency, and reliability.

- Stood up a team focused on IT Operations tooling and enablement to bring the ITSM, CI/CD, DevOps, SRE, and Code Management tooling under a single team. The vision of this team is to enable, empower, and teach the rest of the IT organization how to better use these tools to enable faster and more efficient delivery of code, infrastructure, and vendor applications. This team is also leading the discussion and broadening of Dev-Ops and SRE culture through the entire organization.
- Worked with a team to develop the first chat bots to be used inside of IT to enable the
  gathering of information and speed the time to restore for incidents. These chat bots
  connect to our ITSM systems, Event Management, Knowledge Base, and more to be
  able to quickly gather information on the fly.

# Experience

### DIRECTOR OF SITE RELIABILITY ENGINEERING, MEDIAMATH – MAY 2019-PRESENT

- Given a mandate to move the SRE team from an embedded model to a shared model and build a "Team Mindset". This has been accomplished through knowledge sharing, shared on-call rotations, and team building events
- Began the re-framing of the SLO and Error Budget concepts among the development and engineering teams with a focus on why they are important and how they can help the company reduce loss of revenue due to outages
- Hired multiple new members to the team. These resources have quickly become the highest performing SREs at the company and are the most sought after. Made these hires with the right balance of technical skill and culture/mindset fit so that they could not only hit the ground running, but also be shining examples of the SRE transformation we are undertaking
- Setup the first SRE workshops and monthly stakeholder meetings to begin building a valid and useful dialog between Engineering and Site Reliability Engineering

### IT ENABLEMENT SUPERVISOR, COUNTRY FINANCIAL – 2018-2019

 Took team through first ever Chartering Session building Mission and Vision statements to guide future direction and priority. Focus is on CI/CD, ITSM, SRE, and DevOps tooling and Culture

- Hired 3 open positions focusing on DevOps engineering, Service Management Development, and Scrum/Agile practices
- Lead an initiative to improve on COUNTRY's DevOps Assessment practice to help drive the adoption of DevOps culture and tooling
- Consolidated multiple teams into a single unit with an internal desire to cross train, learn, and grow

#### TIER 2 APPLICATION SUPPORT SUPERVISOR, COUNTRY FINANCIAL - 2017-2018

- Lead team to reduce incident volume by over 12% year over year through automation and problem management
- Implemented the first SRE program at COUNTRY, embedding Tier 2 resources in App Dev teams and taking ownership of reliability and stability of our most important apps
- Built trust in a team that had lost their trust in leadership and put in place real career development and team building practices

## SENIOR IT OPERATIONS ENGINEER / TEAM LEAD, COUNTRY FINANCIAL – 2015-2017

- Lead the maturing of Problem and Major Incident processes. We defined and improved our incident response bridges and communications practices and drove better engagement from support and development teams and their leadership
- Promoted the use of OpenSource software and inner-sourcing practices to build custom tooling to coordinate Incident Response and communications. This project is ongoing.
- Lead a team supporting over 100 applications and on boarding more all the time with a broad range of development environments

#### PROGRAMMER ANALYST, COUNTRY FINANCIAL - 2013-PRESENT

- Developed and enhanced the portal used by all of COUNTRY's agency force and call centers to access customer data and administration systems. Worked with Business Areas to develop requirements.
- Worked on a Mobile and Web application to consolidate Claims Agent assignments and handle workload including real-time live view of adjuster locations and ability to assign based on location.
- Built heatmap style overlays for the Claims unit that would help to understand and predict potential impact of storms through our insured areas

## WEB ADMINISTRATOR, COUNTRY FINANCIAL – 2007-2013

Acted as gatekeeper for multiple internal and external websites. Ensured proper standards and procedures were followed

- Automated multiple manual processes including the updating of over 3000 learning course links automatically with no human intervention saving thousands of man hours
- Built Country's first automated Agent Photo system that created multiple versions of each photo and deployed them to the proper locations.

SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR AND WEB DEVELOPER, MIDILLINI COMMUNICATIONS - 2003-2010

- Managed Linux Based Website Hosting Environments
- Developed Websites and Web Applications
- Consulted and performed small DataCenter moves and upgrades
- Provided Network consulting and installation

## Education

Illinois Wesleyan University – Music Education 1996-1999

Lebanon Community High School - High School Diploma 1996

# Certifications

ITIL v3 Foundations

ITIL v3 Service Operations